A Guide to the Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. (RBI) (and successors) records FA480
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. (RBI) (and successors) records
1936-1985
1946-1983
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers. Inc.
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
Rockefeller, Winthrop (1912-1973)
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
Mauze, Abby Rockefeller (1903-1976)
Woodward, Harper
Venrock
Walkowicz, Thaddeus F.
FA480
207.35 Cubic Feet 512 letter document boxes, 27 legal document boxes, and 1 half-letter document box.
Biographical/Historical note
Capital and standard investing activities of the Rockefeller family began in the 1930s and as efforts expanded after the conclusion of World War II, Rockefeller Brothers Incorporated (RBI) was formed in January 1946 by Laurance S. Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Mauze, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Ted Walkowicz and Harper Woodward to manage the venture capital investments of the Rockefeller family.
RBI started with a capitalization of $1.5 million, and continued operation for approximately 20 years from 1946-1966. In 1969 the Rockefeller family's investments were consolidated into a new organization known as Venrock. Venrock continued Rockefeller efforts to identify and fund entrepreneurs and help to establish the next generation of innovative and enduring companies.
Scope and Contents note
From 1946 through the mid-1980s, all of the filing for the Rockefeller family venture capital investments and the standard investments, as well as the multiple venture firms, was handled by one filing department.
Following procedures established by office management, the standard investment material was routinely destroyed while most of the venture capital material was sent to the Rockefeller family archives. The Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. (and successors) records consists of this venture capital material.
Investments focused in advancements of science and technology, primarily in the areas of aviation, aerospace, communications, computing and data processing, electronics, energy, lasers, optics and physics.
Files for each investment company often include: agreements, by-laws and certificates of incorporation, board of directors and commmittee records, correspondence, financial statements and reports, financing materials, meeting records, workpapers, and documenation of proposals, mergers or dissolutions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Rockefeller Family & Associates physically transferred the Rockefeller Brothers Inc. and successors files to the Rockefeller Archive Center in multiple accessions in 1985.
Related Archival Materials note
Venrock.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research in accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate (January 2019). Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Capital investments; Investments
- Investments, A-Z, Accession 1, 1946-1969; 1936-1984; 1; 97.21 Cubic Feet 251 letter document boxes and 4 legal document boxes; Standard storage boxes, Boxes 1-94.
  - A B C Compound, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Found that application of this "soil conditioner" was too complex and expensive. No interest or investment. TFW.
  - Al-Ber-OX Corp., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Concerned with production of ceramic materials to be used in electronic components. Company still in infancy, information insufficient. No investment. RBM, POC.
  - Ade, E. J. and Co., 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Offer to act as professional fund-raising consultant, JRD declined. Request for financial donations concerning global flight, declined. FDH, JRD, CBS.
  - Advanced Miniaturized Electronics, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Specializes in miniaturized packaging of electronic products. No investment. WJM, TFW.
  - Adela Investment Co., S.A.- Chile-Canadian Mines, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Chile-Canadian Mines. No investment.
  - Aeronca Manufacturing Corp., 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    Aircraft manufacturing. LSR investment. Sale of all LSR stock in 1964. HW, CHB, RBM, LSR.
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Correspondence General, 1951-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Company concerned with the research, development and manufacture of electronic equipment. Investment made. RBM, HW, TFW.
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Directors Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Mergers, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Purchase Negotiations, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Stock and Notes, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Stock Offering, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Airborne Instruments Lab - Summary, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Aircraft Armaments, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Concerned with research and development of electronic, electrical, and mechanical devicies in aviation and manufacture of these for Department of Defense. No investment. HW, POC, CHB.
  - Aircraft Mechanics, Inc., 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Manufacture and inspection of aircraft and related equipment. No investment. HW, POC.
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - General, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Engaged in production and research of mechanical devices for aircraft. Investment made. HW, RBM, FHD.
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Cessna, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Directors, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Diversification - Orien Corp., 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Mergers (Airborne Instrument Lab), 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Stock Interests, 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Aircraft Radio Corp. - Summary (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Air Museum, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Proposed sponsorship of historic aircraft museum. No investment. TFW.
  - Aironics, Inc., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Research and development in field of electronics and electro-mechanical devices. No investment. TFW, HW.
  - Alaska, 1946-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    State industrial development corporation. No investment. RBM, LSR, O. White.
  - Albee Research and Development, 1955-1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Production of rolligon vehicles. No investment. JRD, HW, N. Halaby.
  - Allen Organization, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Park and recreation planners. No investment. RBM.
  - Allied Research Associates - General, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Research and development in fields of nuclear energy and electronics. Investment made. HW, TFW, CHB.
  - Allied Research Associates - Agreements, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Allied Research Associates - Board of Directors meetings, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Allied Research Associates - Capital Expenditures, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Allied Research Associates - Facilities, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Allied Research Associates - Financial Statements and Reviews, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Allied Research Associates - Research and Development, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Allied Research Associates - General Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Allied Research Associates - Shareholders, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Allied Technology, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Development of a service organization offering specialized engineering and management systems in field of automation. No investment. CBS.
  - Alpine Geophysics Associates, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Oceanographic surveyors and instrument manufacturer. No investment.
  - Aluminum Company of Canada, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Purchase of promisory notes. Legal papers re Sleepy Hollow Restorations, Inc. H. Bolton.
  - American Airlines - Annual Reports, 1955-1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Proposed merger with Eastern Airlines. No investment. HW, POC, HD.
  - American Air Liquide, Inc., 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Build plants for the manufacture of gases and related equipment. Investment. JRD, TFW, CBS.
  - American Aircraft, Inc., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Manufacture of aircraft and parts. No investment. HW, POC.
  - American Cryogenics, 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6, Box 6)
    Manufacture and distribution of industrial gases and welding equipment. Investment. HW, TFW, RBM, CBS.
  - American Foldmobile, Co., 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Manufacture and distribution of folding motor scooter. Investment. LSR, RBM, TFW, HW.
  - American Heritage Publishing Company, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Publication of magazines and books. No investment. LSR WJM.
  - American Home Craft, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Cabinet work and design and manufacture of furniture. Investment made. MGR, JRD.
  - American Research and Development Corporation, 1946-1962 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Provide capital for promising business ventures. Investment made. LSR, RBM, HW.
  - American Rocket Society, Inc., 1948-1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Research and development of advanced equipment re field of jet propulsion and rockets. LSR corporate member 1948-1957, individual member 1958-1960.
  - Amotape Oil Company, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Affiliated with Peruvian corporation which is developing its oil properties. No investment. ERH.
  - Anacongo, 1950-1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Pineapple packing in the Belgian Congo. Investment made. LSR, WJM, RBM.
  - Applied Radiation Corp., 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Development of accelerators for industrial radiation processes. Investment made. DR, LSR, TFW, HW, CBS, CHB, JRD.
  - Aqua-Chem, Inc., 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Development of sea water conversion plant in St. Thomas, V.I. No investment. RBM, HW, POC, TFW.
  - Arizona Research Labs, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Construction of solar furnace. No investment. TFW, RBM, N. Halaby.
  - Arkwin Industries, Inc., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Engineering design, manufacturing and sale of hydraulic and pneumatic control devices. Discussion of possible merger between Arkwin and Flight Refueling, but no action. CHB, HW.
  - Athabaska Tar Sands, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Production of crude oil from the tar sands. No investment. TFW, HW, RBM.
  - Atlantic Acceptance Corp., 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Individual and personal financing. No investment. JRD, PB.
  - Bahnson, Agnew, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Manufacturer of humidifying machines. No investment. TFW, HW.
  - Barish, David, 1953-1963 (Box 7, Folder 10, Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    Inventor of aeronautical equipment and devices: vortex ring parachute, flexirotor. LSR financed vortex project. TFW, HW, POC, CHB, LSR.
  - Barish, David - Barish Revisions License Agreement, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Barish, David - Financial (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Barish, David - LSR Agreements (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Barish Associates, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    For Barish inventions. License agreement between PPC and BAI, information on Barish assignment of rights to BAI & related documents. LSR sale of interest.
  - LSR - Pioneer Negotiations, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Barth Engineering and Manufacturing, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Design, development, and manufacture of custom-engineered equipment. No investment. POC, TFW.
  - Baseball Proposal, 1957-1960 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Arrangements for Washington baseball franchise. No investment.
  - Baty, Gordon, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Did masters thesis "Initial Financing of New Research-Based Enterprise in New England." No interest or investment. TFW, CBS.
  - Bede Aircraft Corporation, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Research and development concerning small aircraft. No investment. CBS, TFW, HW.
  - Belgian Congo Investments, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Family's various investments in this country. Investments made. HW, JRD.
  - Bell Aerospace Corp., 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Distribution and manufacture of small helicopters. Parent company is Bell Intercontinental. HW, TFW.
  - Bell Intercontinental, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Production of helicopters and powered wheelbarrows. Interest and investment. CHB, HW, TFW, CES.
  - Benno Bechhold, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Financing of a saving and loan industry in Southern California. JRD, WDD.
  - Billings Farm - Financial, 1949-1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Inheritance of Mary French Rockefeller. Farm and dairy production.
  - Billings Farm - Star Lake Diary, 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Biophysical Electronics, Inc., 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Medical and scientific research and production. Interest. TFW, HW, JRD.
  - Bio-Tronics Research, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Medical and scientific research (anesthesia machine). No investment. RBM, CBS.
  - Birs Dehydration Process, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Dehydration of food stuffs. No investment. JRD.
  - Blyth and Co., Inc., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Brokerage firm. No investment clear. JRD.
  - Bolt Associates, Inc., 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Research, design, development and manufacture of specialized mechanical devices. No investment. CBS, TFW.
  - BONAF (Bonneterie Africaine), 1955-1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Knitting mill. Investment made. WJM.
  - Borax Consolidated, Ltd. - General, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Amalgamation of Anglo-American borate interests with those in South America, Turkey; refinery in Europe. JEL, RHM, TFW, A. Hoover.
  - Borax Consolidated, Ltd. - Directors Meetings, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Borax Consolidated, Ltd. - Background Information, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Borax Consolidated, Ltd. - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 4, Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Borax Consolidated, Ltd. - Financial, 1955-1956 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
  - Bowser, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Liquid control field. No investment. CBS, HW, RBM.
  - Brew, Richard D., Co., 1957-1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Design and production of high vacuum heat treating furnaces. No investment. TFW, RBM.
  - Briarcliff Farms, Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Selective cattle breeding. No investment. FCL, JRD.
  - Brightwater Paper, Co., 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Production of paper and books. No investment. RWP, HW, POC, JRD, TFW.
  - Brunswick Mining & Smelting Corp., 1964-1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Base metal mining. No investment. RHS, FCL, JRD.
  - Bull Line, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Shipping contractor. No investment. RHS, FCL, JRD.
  - Burden, William A. M. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cadillac Color Productions, 1958-1964 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Production of color photo process. Investment made by LSR, DR, WJM, RBM.
  - California Eastern Aviation, 1954-1957 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Air transport operations. No investment. TFW, HW.
  - Callahan, Roy H., 1949-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Personal friend and advisor of LSR. RBM, HW, LSR.
  - CAL-WAL Research and Development Corporation, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Canady, Ward M., 1959-1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Sale of Canady's St. Croix land. Investment by DR & LSR. JRD, HW, RBM.
  - Canborough Corp., 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    No investment. RHS, PB, JRD.
  - Canadian Javelin, Ltd., 1957-1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Mining and development of natural resources. No investment. JRD, RBM.
  - Canandaigua Enterprises Corp., 1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Margaret McGrath Rockefeller interest.
  - Caneel Bay Plantation, 1954-1962 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    Resort hotel in St. John, Virgin Islands. Investment made by LSR. CHB, HW, AB, RBM.
  - Capital for Science, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Financing organization. No investment. TFW, JRD.
  - Caribe Enterprises, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Caribbean Atlantic Airlines, Inc., 1952-1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Airline. LSR investment. JJ, CHB, HW, RMJ.
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Carpenter, Randall H., 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Wayfarer Ketch manager Re LSR investment. CBS, TFW, HW, WJM, AB, RHM.
  - CEGEAC, 1951-1960 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - CEGEAC - Directors Meetings, 1951-1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Automotive distributing agency. Investment made. JJ, WJM, HW, RHM, CHB, AWH, JRD.
  - Cerro Directors Meetings, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3, Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    Mining, mineral and chemical production, smelting operations.
  - Cerro Directors Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Charitable Funds, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Insurance policy proposal for DR. No investment.
  - Charles Center Corp., 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Land development in North Carolina. No investment. WTL, JRD.
  - Chase National Bank, 1949-1963 (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
    DR, LSR.
  - Chateau Lascombes, 1959-1965 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    Wine production. DR investment. WTL, LQM, JRD.
  - Chemical Contour Corp., 1961-1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Investment made: $25,000.
  - Chicago Dock Corp., 1962 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Construction company. No investment clear. WTL, JRD.
  - China Industries, 1945-1955 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Business development in China. RBI investment. OW, JJ, PK, RBM.
  - Cinerama Camera Corp., 1964 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Research and development and production of cineramic equipment. No investment. JRD.
  - Cinerama, Inc., 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Parent company of Cinerama Camera Corp. No investment. JRD.
  - Cohon, Morris and Co., 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    New York security dealers. No investment. RBM.
  - Colchester Gallery, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    LSR investment. RBM, AOM.
  - Colonial Airlines, Inc., 1949-1959 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Airline. LSR investment. HW, RHD.
  - Columbia University - Oral History, 1960-1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Appeal.
  - Commission on Organization of Executive Branch of Government, 1949-1955 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    LSR was advisor. TFW, HW, OW.
  - Committee for International Economic Growth, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Education of relationship between international economic development and the security and welfare of the U.S. NAR was sponsor.
  - Committee for Military Affairs, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with John McCloy. LSR interest.
  - Commonwealth and European Investment Trust (COMMET), 1961-1994 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Financial. LSR investment. RHS, JRD, PB.
  - Compagnie Internationale de Placements et de Capitalisation, 1963-1968 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Investment company. No investment. RHS, JRD.
  - Compagnie Miron Limitee, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Production and marketing of concrete and related construction. No investment. JRD, RHS.
  - Computone Systems - Directors Meetings, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 10, Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Controls Company of America, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    No investment.
  - Cooper, Tinsley Labs, 1961-1963 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Development, manufacture and marketing of pharmaceutical and chemical supplies. No investment. RBM, JRD.
  - Cornell Aeronautical Labs, Inc., 1949-1962 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Research and development in field of aeronautics. LSR investment. TFW, RBM.
  - Cotton Bay Club, Ltd., 1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Golf club in Bahamas. No investment. JRD.
  - Craig Systems, 1955-1960 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Production of communications equipment. No investment.
  - Cranmer, Robert L., 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Mining concern. No investment. RHS, WTL.
  - Crawford de Mexico, S.A., 1957-1965 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Sale and distribution of food stuffs (Shopping Center) LSR investment. RBM, WJM.
  - Cryogenic Engineering Co., Inc., 1962-1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    DuPont affiliate.
  - Cryogenics Corp., 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Cryonetics - Audits, 1962-1967 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Subsidiary of Cryogenics. Investment made. CHB, CBS, TFW, HW, PB, WB, RBM, JRD, RHS.
  - Cryonetics - Directors Meetings, 1962-1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Cryonetics - Financing, 1962-1967 (Box 22, Folder 3-4, Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Cryonetics - General, 1962-1967 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Cryonetics - Mergers (Magnion), 1962-1967 (Box 24, Folder 1-3, Box 25, Folder 2-3)
  - Cryonetics - Reference Summary (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Cryonetics - Stockholders Meetings (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Curtis Publishing Co., 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    No investment. PB, JRD.
  - Custer Channel Wing Aircraft, 1949-1965 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Cutler-Hammer, Inc. - General, 1958-1968 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Electrical controls. DR & LSR investment. RBM, HW, WJM, JRD, PB.
  - Cutler-Hammer, Inc. - Airborne Instruments Labs Merger, 1959-1962 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Cutler-Hammer, Inc. - Airborne Instruments Labs (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Cutler-Hammer, Inc. - Directors Meetings, 1960-1968 (Box 26, Folder 3, Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Cutler-Hammer, Inc. - Board Meeting Material, 1963-1968 (Box 26, Folder 4, Box 27, Folder 3, Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Datatype Corp., 1965 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Manufacture and sale of magnetic tapes for computers. No investment. WJM.
  - Dean, Norman L., 1960 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Dean system space drive. No investment. TFW, RBM.
  - Defense Research Corp., 1960-1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Scientific research of defense systems. No investment. WJM, TFW, CHB, HW.
  - Deltec Investment and Development, S.A., 1958-1961 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    LSR investment. WJM, RWP, REM.
  - Dickson Electronics Corp., 1965 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    Analyses.
  - R.S. Dickson and Company, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Digitronics Corp., 1960-1968 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    Data processing equipment. No investment. WJM, POC, HW.
  - Disarmament, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    Interest shown. HW.
  - Donner Electronics, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    Supplier of control devices to industry. No investment. JRD, RBM, WJM, CES.
  - Dorado Beach Development, 1954-1963 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    LSR Hotel Project. LSR and NAR investment. AB, RBM, PK, WJM, HW.
  - Dorado Beach Development - General, 1954-1963 (Box 30, Folder 3-4, Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Dorado Beach Development - Airport, 1958-1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Dorado Beach Development - Caribbean Enterprises, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Dracone Operations, 1960-1962 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Water-carrying containers. No investment. TFW, AB, RBM.
  - Draper, Gaither and Anderson, 1959-1963 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Private investment banking firm. Family investments. JRD, REM, HW, TFW.
  - Drum Publications, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    South African publication. No investment. REM.
  - DuPont, Francis I. and Company, 1950-1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Brokerage and investment firm. Interest shown.
  - Dynatech Corp., 1959-1965 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Electronic research, analysis. No investment. POC, CBS.
  - East African Printers, Ltd., 1959 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    No investment. JRD.
  - Eastern Airlines - Clippings, 1937-1958 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    LSR Investment. RBM, HW, TFW, FHD, WJM, RHS, POC.
  - Eastern Airlines - Credit Arrangements, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Airlines - Correspondence, 1941-1963 (Box 32, Folder 7, Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Airlines - Civil Aeronautics Board (CAB) - Interlocking Relationships, 1939-1963 (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
  - Eastern Airlines - Civil Aeronautics Board (CAB) - Colonial Airlines Merger, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
  - Eastern Airlines - Civil Aeronautics Act (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Airlines - Financing - Documents, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 4, Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Airlines - Directors Meetings, 1947-1963 (Box 35, Folder 2-3, Box 36, Folder 1-3, Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Eastern Airlines - Financial, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Airlines - Financial Reports, 1939-1957 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Airlines - Financing, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Airlines - West Coast Agenda, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Airlines - Projections - Forecasts, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 4)